<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><title>Annual Small Area Population and Household Estimates, Twin Cities Metropolitan Area</title><origin>Metropolitan Council</origin><pubinfo><publish>Metropolitan Council</publish></pubinfo><pubdate>periodically revised</pubdate><onlink>https://gisdata.mn.gov/dataset/us-mn-state-metc-society-small-area-estimates</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>This dataset consists of housing unit, household, and population estimates for census tracts, census block groups, Transportation Analysis Zones (TAZs), school districts, and ZIP codes in the Twin Cities Region. These data provide a more precise and timely picture of current conditions than the American Community Survey, another source of small area data. It may be possible to calculate estimates for other small areas upon request; contact Research@metc.state.mn.us for more information.</abstract><purpose>This dataset consists of housing unit, household, and population estimates for census tracts, census block groups, Transportation Analysis Zones (TAZs), school districts, and ZIP codes in the Twin Cities Region. These data provide a more precise and timely picture of current conditions than the American Community Survey, another source of small area data. It may be possible to calculate estimates for other small areas upon request; contact Research@metc.state.mn.us for more information.</purpose><supplinf>Twin Cities seven-county metropolitan area.  This includes the counties of Anoka, Carver, Dakota, Hennepin, Ramsey, Scott and Washington in Minnesota. Estimates for Transportation Analysis Zones also include counties that are contiguous to the region (Chisago, Goodhue, Isanti, Le Sueur, McLeod, Rice, Sherburne, Sibley, and Wright Counties in Minnesota and Pierce, Polk, and St. Croix Counties in Wisconsin).</supplinf></descript><timeperd><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20190401</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo><current>2019 estimates published July 2020. Please contact Matt Schroeder (contact information below) for historical data tables.</current></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>Annually</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-94.012</westbc><eastbc>-92.732</eastbc><northbc>45.415</northbc><southbc>44.471</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><place><placekey>Twin Cities, Anoka County, Carver County, Dakota County, Hennepin County, Ramsey County, Scott County, Washington County, Chisago County, Goodhue County, Isanti County, Le Sueur County, McLeod County, Rice County, Sherburne County, Sibley County, Wright County, Pierce County, Polk County, St. Croix County</placekey></place><theme><themekey>population, households, annual estimates, census, tract, block group, TAZ, Transportation Analysis Zones, ZIP code, ZCTA, school district</themekey><themekt>None</themekt></theme></keywords><accconst>None. This dataset is public domain under the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13). If the dataset is not available from the Online Linkage in Section 6, please contact the Distribution Contact Person.</accconst><browse><browsen>none available</browsen></browse><native>Oracle Version 10g, Release 2</native><crossref><citeinfo><title>Census Geography 2010 - Realigned Block, BlockGroup &amp; Tract; Transportation Analysis Zones (Official TAZ System w/3,030 Zones) with Current Forecasts; School District Boundaries, Minnesota, SY 2019-2020; ZIP Code Tabulation Areas, 5-digit (ZCTA5), Minnesota, 2010</title></citeinfo></crossref><useconst>None. This dataset is public domain under the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13).</useconst><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Metropolitan Council</cntorg><cntper>Matt Schroeder</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Senior Researcher</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>390 Robert Street North</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55101-1805</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651.602.1513</cntvoice><cntemail>matt.schroeder@metc.state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>By definition, estimates are only approximations of the characteristics of an area at a point in time. These estimates are based on the best available information provided by local governments, U.S. Census Bureau, and U.S. Postal Service. They are also designed to be consistent with city and township estimates from the Metropolitan Council and, for TAZs in "collar counties," estimates from the Minnesota State Demographic Center and Wisconsin Demographic Services Center (TAZs in "collar counties" only). See the estimates methodology, available via metrocouncilorg/populationestimates, for an explanation of the calculations. </attraccr></attracc><complete>Entire seven-county geographic area is covered. Transportation Analysis Zone estimates also cover "collar counties" (those contiguous to the seven-county region).</complete><lineage><procstep>Historical data may be available for the following places:

Burns Township (became the city of Nowthen, July 2008)
Chaska Township (merged with the city of Chaska, January 2005)
Columbus Township (became the city of Columbus, September 2006)
Elko (merged with the city of New Market to become Elko New Market, January 2007)
Forest Lake Township (merged with the city of Forest Lake, March 2000)
Grant Township (became the city of Grant, January 1997)
Hassan Township (merged with the city of Rogers, January 1, 2012)
New Market (merged with the city of Elko to become Elko New Market, January 2007)
New Scandia Township (became the city of Scandia, January 2007)
Norwood (merged with the city of Young America to become Norwood Young America, January 1997)
Oak Grove Township (became the city of Oak Grove, December 1993)
Young America (merged with the city of Norwood to become Norwood Young America, January 1997)</procstep></lineage></dataqual><spdoinfo><mgmg3obj /><mgmg3til /><indspref /><direct /></spdoinfo><spref><vertdef><altsys><altdatum>not applicable</altdatum><altunits>NA</altunits></altsys><depthsys><depthdn>NA</depthdn><depthdu>NA</depthdu></depthsys></vertdef></spref><eainfo><overview><eaover>STATE: FIPS code for state (Minnesota = 27; Wisconsin = 55)
CO_CODE: FIPS code for county, available for tract/block group/TAZ estimates only
TR10: FIPS code for census tracts, available for tract estimates only (digits 1-2 = state; digits 3-5 = county; digits 6-11 = tract)
BG10: FIPS code for census block groups, available for block group estimates only (digits 1-2 = state; digits 3-5 = county; digits 6-11 = tract; digit 12 = block group)
TAZ_2010: Code for Transportation Analysis Zone (TAZ), available for TAZ estimates only
UNI_TYP: Type of school district, available for school district estimates only (1 = independent; 3 = special)
SDNUM: School district identifier, available for school district estimates only
SDNAME: School district name, available for school district estimates only
ZCTA5: ZIP Code Tabulation Area identifier, available for ZCTA estimates only
PARTIALGEO: Indicator for whether the estimate represents the complete geography or only part of it, available for school district and ZCTA estimates only (1 = geography lies partly outside the seven-county Twin Cities region, and estimate is only for the portion inside the region)
EST_YEAR: Year of current estimate (2019)
HU_EST: Total housing units, current estimate
HH_EST: Total households, current estimate
POP_EST: Total population, current estimate
POPHH_EST: Population in households, current estimate
POPGQ_EST: Population in group quarters, current estimate</eaover><eadetcit>None</eadetcit></overview></eainfo><distinfo><resdesc>Annual Small Area Population and Household Estimates</resdesc><distliab>NOTICE: The Geographic Information System (GIS) Data to which this notice is attached are made available pursuant to the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13). THE GIS DATA ARE PROVIDED TO YOU AS IS AND WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY AS TO THEIR PERFORMANCE, MERCHANTABILITY, OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE. The GIS Data were developed by the Metropolitan Council for its own internal business purposes. The Metropolitan Council does not represent or warrant that the GIS Data or the data documentation are error-free, complete, current, or accurate. You are responsible for any consequences resulting from your use of the GIS Data or your reliance on the GIS Data. You should consult the data documentation for this particular GIS Data to determine the limitations of the GIS Data and the precision with which the GIS Data may depict distance, direction, location, or other geographic features. If you transmit or provide the GIS Data (or any portion of it) to another user, it is recommended that the GIS Data include a copy of this disclaimer and this metadata.</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>csv file</formname><formvern>NA</formvern><transize>Less than 1 MB for zip file</transize></digtinfo></digform><ordering>See "Online Linkage" below</ordering></stdorder><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Metropolitan Council</cntorg><cntper>Matt Schroeder</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Senior Researcher</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>390 Robert Street North</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55101-1805</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651.602.1513</cntvoice><cntemail>matt.schroeder@metc.state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20200723</metd><metstdn>Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines</metstdn><metstdv>1.2</metstdv><metextns><onlink>http://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/committee/standards/mgmg/metadata.htm</onlink></metextns><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Metropolitan Council</cntorg><cntper>Matt Schroeder</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Senior Researcher</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>390 Robert Street North</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55101-1805</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651.602.1513</cntvoice><cntemail>matt.schroeder@metc.state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><Esri><ModDate>20110321</ModDate><ModTime>08360600</ModTime></Esri><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20110321</mdDateSt></metadata>